《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
STARBUCK: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
李奥本是一个非常狡猾的赛昂人 他会想方设法迷惑你
ADAMA: Leoben is a very clever Cylon. He's gonna try to get into your head.
我们还没正式介绍过
We haven't been properly introduced.
我是李奥本
I'm Leoben.
审讯那个赛昂人
ROSLIN: I want the Cylon interrogated.
动手
Do it.
这一切都发生过
This has happened before.
这一切会再次重演
And all of it will happen again.
你的一切皆已是命中注定
Your destiny has already been written.
我看过你的X光片
I saw your x-rays.
你身上有多处童年时留下的骨折
A lot of old fractures from childhood.
有虐儿倾向的父母...
Children of abusive parents
他们的子女 通常也会惧怕自己重蹈覆辙
often fear passing along that abuse to their own children.
出去!
Get out!
我是在帮助你  卡拉
I'm trying to help you, Kara.
只想让你认清你生活的本来面目
I only want you to see the truth of your life.
你饱受煎熬的原因 你长久以来痛苦挣扎的原因
The reason why you suffered. The reason why you struggled for so long.
如果李奥本所言有关你和你那与众不同的宿命确有其事呢?
What if there's something to what Leoben said about you and a special destiny?
"卡拉・瑟瑞丝和她与众不同的宿命"?
Kara Thrace and her special destiny?
听起来更像是一支不入流的乐队
That sounds more like a bad cover band, Sam.
这颗新星看起来确实像神庙里的曼荼罗
ADAMA: I think the nova does look like the mandala inside this temple.
也许它正是一块...
Maybe it was a road sign.
指明他们去向的路标
Showing the direction that they headed to next.
让我好奇的是...
HELO: I'm curious about something.
你在卡布里卡的家里所作的那幅画
Those paintings you did, from your apartment on Caprica.
这是神庙里的图案
This was on the Temple.
你的那幅画从哪里得来的灵感?
Where did you get the idea to paint yours?
我从小就那么乱涂了 我喜欢那个图案
That's just something I've been doodling since I was a kid. I like the pattern.
他们在4000年前建造的神庙
Well, they built the Temple 4,000 years ago.
怎么了?
What is it?
李奥本有一次曾说过...
Just something Leoben said once.
我有我的宿命
That I had a destiny.
一切都已是命中注定
That it had already been written.
怎么了?
What's up?
没事  睡觉去
Nothing. Go back to sleep.
起得早啊
You're up early.
你不也一样
You, too.
恩
Yeah.
赫拉总是做噩梦
Hera gets these nightmares.
醒来以后  又哭又闹   全身哆嗦
Wakes up crying and shaking.
哄她睡着以后  我倒精神了
By the time we calm her down and get her back to sleep, I'm wide awake.
在新卡布里卡上经历的那些破事 真的给她留下了心理阴影
All that crap she went through on New Caprica really left its mark on her.
恩  我理解她
Yeah, I know just how she feels.
要是你没给我看过那张讨厌的曼荼罗图片多好
Wish you never would've showed me the picture of that frakking mandala.
我他妈每晚都会梦见…
I dream about it and that bastard Leoben
它和李奥本那个狗杂种
every gods-damned night.
觉得自己都快精神失常了
I feel like I'm losing my mind here.
卡拉  仁川号上有一名心理医生
You know, Kara, there's a psychiatrist aboard Inchon Velle.
我们已经为赫拉安排了一个约会 你可以考虑去她那里看一下
We've made an appointment for Hera. Maybe you should think about seeing her.
逗我?
You kidding me?
大部分心理医生比他们的患者还猪头
Most shrinks are more frakked up than their patients are.
去拜访一下住在道格维尔的那位先知吧
You know, you might want to check out that oracle camped in Dogsville.
据说她会解梦
People say she interprets dreams.
能占星卜命  洞悉玄机
Sees things in them. Predicts events.
嗨
Hey.
没事吧?
You okay?
不知道
I don't know.
喂?
Hello?
奥罗拉女神
BRENN: The goddess Aurora.
拿去吧 归你了
Take it. It's yours.
我要这玩意有什么用?
What the hell am I going to do with this?
到时你自会明白
You'll know when the time comes.
坐吧
Sit.
我… 我睡不着
I... I can't sleep.
总是做噩梦
Having these nightmares.
梦到那个赛昂人
About the Cylon.
那个在新卡布里卡上监禁你的赛昂人
The one who held you captive on New Caprica,
李奥本
Leoben.
我知道他只是…
I know that he was just...
他要比你还要了解你自己
He knows you better than you know yourself,
卡拉・瑟瑞丝
Kara Thrace.
他看清了你的本来面目
He sees the truth about you.
你的宿命
About your destiny.
你并不…
You don't...
够了
Enough of that.
我唯一的宿命就是成为世界级的冒失鬼
The only destiny I have is as a world-class frak-up.
专门伤害关心你的人
Who hurts everyone she cares about.
这是拜你母亲所赐  对吧?
That was your mother's gift to you, wasn't it?
一位信奉苦痛有益于灵魂的女人生下了你
You were born to a woman who believed suffering was good for the soul,
所以你只能受苦
so you suffered.
你的一生与痛苦为伴
BOTH: Your life is a testament to pain.
你想要相信这一点 因为…
You want to believe it because
这说明你时运不济...  这说明你时运不济
it means that you're bad luck. ... it means that you're bad luck.
你像是癌细胞 你像是癌细胞
You're like a cancer You're like a cancer
需要被切除 需要被切除
that needs to be removed. that needs to be removed.
因为你每天都能听到她的声音 因为你每天都能听到她的声音
Because you hear her voice every day. Because you hear her voice every day.
而你希望她所说的都是真的 而你希望她所说的都是真的
And you want her to be right. And you want her to be right.
李奥本对我说的话  是别人告诉你的吗?
Somebody told you what Leoben said to me.
你对别人说过这些话么?
Did you ever tell anyone about that?
你错误地领会了你母亲的意图 卡拉
You learned the wrong lesson from your mother, Kara.
你把信息和信使弄混淆了
You confused the messenger with the message.
你母亲要教授给你的是其他东西
Your mother was trying to teach you something else.
你他妈并不了解我母亲
You don't know crap about my mother.
李奥本了解
Leoben does.
他能看到那些图案
He sees the patterns.
看到它们如何拼凑到一起   闭嘴
Sees how it all fits together. Shut up.
他会来找你
BRENN: He's coming for you.
很快
Soon.
你他妈给我闭嘴
Shut the frak up.
你无法阻止他
You can't stop him.
他会为你领路
And he will show you the way.
还有半小时  我就要乘飞梭走了
I'm on a shuttle in a half an hour.
去请假和我走吧
Ask for your leave and come with me.
你还可以休息一下
You could use the downtime.
好有诱惑力
It sounds tempting.
那就来吧
So do it.
没有条件 我们都不用谈论感情问题
No strings, okay? We don't even have to talk about our relationship.
我考虑一下
I'll think about it.
就是说没戏了
Which means, "No. "
有些事我不愿去提
You know, I hate to say this.
可那个神道的先知说得很有道理
But that whack-job oracle, she's got a point.
早在李奥本之前  你母亲就已经把你教坏了
Your mother frakked up your head long before Leoben ever got to you.
有很多事让她操心 山姆
She was dealing with a lot, Sam.
她说我与别的孩子不同
She told me that I was different from other kids.
我要成为一名像她一样的战士
That I needed to be a warrior, like her.
她教我"畏惧会让你死掉"
Taught me that fear gets you killed,
"愤怒会让你活命"
and anger keeps you alive.
她做的那些让你气愤的事还少么?
Well, she gave you plenty to be angry about, didn't she?
因为你没叠被
Split your head open with a broomstick handle
就用笤帚把劈你的脑袋
because you didn't make your bed?
我有没有告诉过你我怎么报复她?
I ever tell you how I got back at her?
没有
No.
在第一次赛昂大战期间
During the first Cylon war,
她随第一批陆战队驻守在麦加
she was stationed with the first marines on Mehidra.
你可不知道那些丛林里有多臭
Stinking jungles you wouldn't believe.
从此 她就对昆虫有了恐惧症
Had this phobia of insects for the rest of her life.
讨厌那些该死的东西
Hated the damn things.
于是我就去买了一些橡胶制成的虫子
So I go out and I buy a bunch of rubber bugs
然后溜进了她的衣橱
and I slip into her closet
把它们都放到了她的鞋子上
and I put them all over her shoes.
然后呢?
And?
把她吓得魂都没了
She screamed her frakking head off.
然后我走进她的房间
I go in
看到她正用鞋子来拍它们
and she's trying to smash them with her shoes
结果越拍它们跳得越厉害
but that's just making them bounce around even more.
你肯定挨收拾了
You must have caught hell for that.
她抓住我的手按在门框上 然后用门来夹
She grabbed my hand, held it in the doorjamb and slammed the door.
真没想到
Frak me.
不过也算值得了
It was worth it, though.
上尉  我是卡拉狄加  我们有几个阀门失灵
MAN: Captain, it's Galactica. We've had a couple of valve failures.
要重新开始注水
We're re-starting the unrep.
这可好
STARBUCK: That's just great.
热狗  别急  我们还要在这里呆上三个小时
Hotdog, settle in. We're gonna be out here for another three hours.
热狗  你在干什么?
Hotdog, what the hell are you doing?
再次享受蓝天白云
HOTDOG: Enjoying blue skies again.
这也是我唯一留恋新卡布里卡的地方
About the only thing I miss about New Caprica.
卡拉狄加  我是星芭  好戏开始了
Galactica, it's Starbuck. Showtime.
一架不明战机出现在我右方一点45000尺的云层里  作战开始
Bogey. My right one, in the soup at 45. Committing.
星芭  我是热狗 未发现敌机   加速
Starbuck, Hotdog. No joy. Press.
取消注水 立即取出那些燃料管
Abort the un-rep. Unhook those fuel lines immediately.
补给船  我是卡拉狄加
Refueling ships, Galactica.
立即停止一切补给行动
Immediate. Cease all underway replenishment ops.
雷达上可以看到星芭和热狗
Sir, we've got both Starbuck and Hotdog on dradis
并未发现不明战机
but no contact on the bogey.
能看到就算走运了
We're lucky we can see anything.
自从我们到了这里...
That planet's synchrotron radiation
那颗行星的同步辐射
has been kicking the crap out of every dradis in the fleet
就把雷达都搞得一团糟
since we got here.
要找一处安稳之地藏起来为舰队补给就要付出代价
Price you pay for a good place to hide and refuel the fleet.
看来也是赛昂突袭机绝佳的藏身之地
Looks like it's also a good place for hiding a Cylon Raider.
星芭  我是阿波罗  什么情况?
Starbuck, Apollo. What have you got?
阿波罗 有一架重型突袭机正和我们在云层里捉迷藏
Apollo, we've got one turkey playing hide and seek in the clouds.
没有同伴  采取攻击
No sparrows. Engaging offensive.
一架重型突袭机 没有战机护航
One heavy Raider. No fighter escort.
雷达上还是没有敌机
GAETA: Still no bandits on dradis.
如果让那混蛋跳跃走 赛昂人在几分钟内就会出现在我们眼前
If that bastard jumps, the Cylons could be all over us in minutes.
警告舰队准备进行紧急跳跃
Alert the fleet to stand by for an emergency jump.
星芭  我是热狗  没有发现突袭机 我快看不到你了
Starbuck, Hotdog. No visual on your Raider and I'm losing you!
见鬼  星芭 什么都看不见了 重复一遍 我在云层里看不到你
Damn it, Starbuck. Blind! I say again, I lost you in the clouds!
星芭 我们在雷达上未发现你所说的敌机
APOLLO: Starbuck, we have no dradis contact on your bogey.
你能看到吗?
Do you have visual?
能  他躲在了云层里  只是藏在了风暴系统里
Affirmative. He's hiding in the clouds. He just ducked into the storm system.
你能看到他吗?  能看到他吗?
APOLLO: Do you see? Do you see him?
卡拉狄加 我是星芭 准备开火
Galactica, Starbuck. Tally. Weapons hot.
卡拉狄加 我是星芭 受到一次撞击 仍能飞行
Galactica, Starbuck. Took a hit. Still flying.
星芭儿  你能行吗?
APOLLO: Starbuck, are you nominal?
机腹受撞  但一切正常
STARBUCK: Got me under the chin. Everything's green.
那架突袭机到底在哪里?
Where the hell is that Raider?
长官 星芭正在俯冲飞向该行星的最低海拔高度
Sir, Starbuck's dropping close to the planetary hard deck.
如果她保持航线 大气密度将使她…
If she stays on course, the atmospheric density
无法再次返回轨道
will keep her from reaching orbit again.
压力会把她像易拉罐一样挤扁
And then the pressure will crush her like a cheap soda can.
星芭  你飞得太低了 改变航向  爬升
APOLLO: Starbuck, you're getting too low. Break off and climb.
重复一遍 星芭  你飞得太低  改变航向  爬升
I repeat. Starbuck, you're getting too low. Break off and climb.
星芭!
Starbuck.
星芭  在你被压碎之前快上拉
Starbuck, pull out before you don't have the smash to regain orbit.
卡拉  说话
Kara, come in.
她到底要去那里?
ADAMA: Where the hell is she going?
星芭...
APOLLO: Starbuck?
离开那里
Get out of there.
星芭  说话  收到了吗?
Starbuck, come in. Do you read?
星芭  你飞得太低  改变航向  爬升
Starbuck, you're getting too low. Break off and climb.
飞起来
Get up.
热狗  你能看到星芭吗?
Hotdog, do you have a visual on Starbuck?
星芭  说话  收到了吗?!  星芭  上拉!
Starbuck, come in! Do you read? Starbuck! Pull up!
这是命令 上拉
That is an order. Pull out!
阿波罗  我是星芭  照办
Apollo, Starbuck. Wilco.
来吧!
Come on!
哪里被撞了  轮机长?
Where'd I take the hits, Chief?
看来哪都没有  上尉
Looks like nowhere, Captain.
什么?  我感受到撞击了
What? I felt the impact!
该死的蝮蛇机像是撞在了墙上
Damn Viper felt like it hit a brick wall.
我们会继续检查 不过目前看来毫发无伤
Well, we'll keep checking. But so far, not a scratch.
天杀的  肯定就在那里    再放一遍
Gods damn it, it has to be there. Run it again.
已经看两遍了
We've watched it twice already.
那这就不是我的照相枪
Then this isn't my gun camera film.
别人一天都没开过枪
ATHENA: No one else pulled a trigger all day.
我们对比了卡拉狄加与猛禽机上的雷达记录
We checked Galactica's dradis records against the ones in our Raptor.
根本没有赛昂人的影子
There was no paint on your Cylon at all.
大家都清楚 雷达到了这星球附近的时候靠不住
And we all know that dradis can be wonky near this planet, Karl.
也许在你开火之前  突袭机就已经跳跃走了
Maybe the Raider jumped away before you opened fire.
或许本来就没有
Or maybe it never existed to begin with.
它肯定在那里
It was there.
要让她禁飞?
Gonna ground her?
科特尔说她身体合格  可却是一个容易激动的疯子
Cottle says she's physically fit, but an emotional basket case.
在和平时期我们都得被禁飞
In peacetime, he'd ground us all.
那还是把球踢给你了
So it falls back on you.
对
Yeah.
就算是个冒失鬼 她仍旧是我手下最出色的蝮蛇机驾驶员
Even screwed up, she's still the best Viper driver I've got.
有时要承认我们中最出色的一员
Sometimes it's hard to admit that the best of us
也会累垮并不是容易的事
can burn out.
你认为她是这样吗?
Do you think she has?
不知道
I don't know.
我想作为一名技艺超群的蝮蛇机驾驶员...
I think her identity as a steely-eyed Viper jock
是唯一让她不至于崩溃的原因
is the only thing holding her together.
所以如果我让她禁飞...
So, then, if I ground her...
每个人都有忧虑不安的时候
Everyone gets rattled sometimes.
但根本问题是...
But the bottom line is,
当子弹纷飞的时候
when the bullets start to fly,
她是否能应付得来?
can she handle it?
当你"光荣"的时候  你想被放在哪里?
So, where do you want to go when you bite the big one?
我想在小凯身边
I want to go right there, next to Kat.
一位水上漂的蝮蛇机驾驶员
A water-walking Viper jock.
十足的讨厌鬼  可有她做你僚机却是好帮手
A royal pain in the ass, but a hell of a stick to have on your wing.
你可以把我放在这里
You can put me right here.
放在达克和罗拉旁边
Next to Duck and Nora.
玩牌高手
Good card players.
永远有此陪伴也不错
Nice way to spend eternity.
好 如果谁先挂了
Okay. So whoever croaks first, the other one makes sure
另一个人可要把照片放对地方 说定了?
that their picture goes in the right place. Deal?
一言为定
Deal.
老头子对我的作战报告有什么看法?
So, what did the old man have to say about my combat report?
"星芭终于陷入了困境"?
Starbuck's finally gone off the deep end.
"无法胜任工作"?
Unfit for duty?
他说我是队长 由我决定
He said I'm the CAG. It's my call.
啊…
Ah.
那你怎么说?
And what do you say?
我说比起雷达 我更相信你的眼睛
Well, I say I'd trust your eyes over dradis any day of the week.
可能确实有东西在那里  在云中消失了
Something could have been there and vanished in the cloud cover.
你认为我不是疯子?
So, you don't think I'm nuts?
我可没那么说 你是个胡说八道的疯子
I didn't say that. You're a raving lunatic.
我从第一次看到你 你就疯疯癫癫的
As demented and deranged as the first day I met you.
你是个混球
And you're a bastard.
听着
Look,
压力可以让我们大家都变得神经质
stress has made us all twitchy.
在新卡布里卡上那个赛昂人对你所做的一些事之后
After what that Cylon put you through on New Caprica,
有些事你并没说
you've had more than your share.
休息一下吧
Get some rest
不然你真的会开始出现幻觉
or you will start seeing things.
好
Yeah.
这样还有六艘民用船等待补给
That leaves six civvies in line to refuel.
那再等10个小时  我们就完工了?
ROSLIN: So, another 10 hours and we're done.
恩
ADAMA: Yeah.
星芭?
Starbuck?
你听到了什么?
What do you hear?
只有雨声
Nothing but the rain.
那就带上你的枪  把猫请进来
Then grab your gun and bring in the cat.
遵命  上将
Wilco, Admiral.
总统阁下
Madam President.
上尉
Captain.
感觉怎么样?
How is it out there?
我会检讨的
Hell of a view.
我们就快完成补给了
We're almost to the finish line.
可以跳出这个星系
Then we can jump the hell out of this system.
同心协力
So say we all.
嗯…
Um...
抱歉  老大
Actually... Sorry, Boss.
有些东西要送给你
I have something for you.
我觉得拿这个作为您木船模型的破浪神不错
I thought that it would be a nice figurehead for your model ship.
奥罗拉
Aurora.
黎明女神  对
Goddess of the dawn. Yeah.
她会带来晨星与和风
She brings the morning star and a fair wind.
一个崭新的开始
A fresh start.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝你好运
Good hunting.
谢谢
Thank you.
线束装配?
Harness assembly?
腰肩部固定销已经安装好
Lap and shoulder retaining pins installed.
收缩卷正确
Retraction reel correct.
刚连接块锁定指示器  显示黄旗
Disconnect block locking indicator. Yellow flag visible.
没事吧  上尉?
TYROL: You all right, Captain?
呃…
Uh...
让我单独呆一会  轮机长
Give me a minute here, Chief.
我们没说过吗?
WOMAN: Did we not talk about it?
快点 拜托  停下来!
Do it! Come on, do, it! Stop it!
少校
TYROL: Major.
她就那样坐在那里
She's just sitting there.
你和她谈过了么?
Well, did you talk to her?
你去和她谈谈吧
You talk to her.
替我难过?
Feeling sorry for me?
卡拉… 每个人都有忧虑不安的时候
Kara, everyone gets rattled.
即便是最出色的人
Even the best.
我不会回去了
I'm not going back out there.
我不相信我自己
I don't trust myself.
嗯
Hmm.
那就相信我
So trust me.
我做你的僚机
I'll fly your wing.
空军队长做我下手
The CAG flying my number two?
让我干什么都行
Whatever it takes.
你和小杜的事怎么样了?
How are things with you and Dee?
呃…
Uh...
挺好的
You know. Good.
不
No.
比那还要强
Better than good.
最好的时候
Best they've ever been.
我替你高兴
I'm happy for you.
真的
Really.
有意思的是 在我们一起经历了这么多以后
It's funny though, after all we've been through
我们又回到了原点
we are right back where we started.
你还是空军队长  我还是你的王牌蝮蛇机驾驶员
You're CAG and I am your hotshot problem pilot.
看来我们只能是这样的关系了
I guess that's all we'll ever be now, huh?
星芭  我是阿波罗  感觉怎么样?
Starbuck, Apollo. How we doing?
好极了
Copacetic.
再过30分钟 我们就返回基地
Another 30 minutes and we head back to the barn.
见鬼 阿波罗  一架敌机 在我右边三点钟方向出现
Damn it. Apollo! One turkey, my right, three,
十点钟高度  潜入云层中
level at 10, ducking in and out of the clouds.
追击
Engaging.
星芭  我是阿波罗 未发现敌机
Starbuck, Apollo. No joy.
星芭  我是卡拉狄加
Starbuck, Galactica.
雷达上并未发现赛昂人
No dradis contact on your Cylon.
阿波罗  我是星芭
Apollo, Starbuck.
准备开火 作战开始
Weapons hot. Committing.
这次我要把这混蛋拖回去 扔到机库里
This time I'm gonna drag him back and dump his sorry ass on the hangar deck.
全体舰队一级戒备 解开所有燃料管
Set the fleet at condition one. Uncouple the hoses!
星芭  我是阿波罗 我无法在雷达上看到你
Starbuck, Apollo. I've lost you on dradis.
我什么都不看见
I'm blind!
星芭  我是阿波罗  重复一遍 我看不到你或突袭机
Starbuck, Apollo. I repeat. I've got no sign of you or the Raider.
星芭 报告
Starbuck! Report!
星芭  报告
Starbuck, report!
我是阿波罗  收到了吗?
This is Apollo. Do you read me?
星芭  报告
Starbuck! Report!
星芭!
Starbuck!
星芭  我的能见度为零
Starbuck, I have zero visibility.
星芭  你在吗?
Starbuck, are you out there?
卡拉!
Kara!
早安  特尔斐
D.J.: Good morning, Delphi.
今天又是炎热的一天 是去海滩的时候了
Got another hot one in store for you today. Time to head for the beach.
天气预报员说…
Weatherman says we can...
太阳照屁股了
Rise and shine.
今天可是个大日子
We have a big day ahead of us.
得了
Come on.
我没在这里
I'm not here.
我在寒冷的屋外
I'm out cold.
不然就是在赛昂母舰上
Or on a Cylon ship
你把我拉进来和你玩那个荒诞的心理游戏
and you drag me to play your frakking mind games.
没有游戏  卡拉
No games, Kara.
是关于你宿命的事
That's not your destiny.
我自己谱写我的命运
I write my own destiny.
不是我绘制的那个符号  卡拉
I didn't paint that symbol, Kara.
而是你
You did.
你在云里
You saw it again.
又看到了它
In the clouds.
对吧?
Didn't you?
你没有告诉别人
But you didn't tell anyone else.
因为你陷于其中
Because you're drawn to it.
你能感受到它的吸引力
You feel its pull.
你想飞到它的里面 穿过它
You want to fly into it. You want to cross over.
但你害怕
But you're afraid.
怕什么?  就怕一片他妈的云彩?
Afraid of what? A frakking cloud?
未知的事情
Of the unknown.
死亡
Death.
你所有的特技都是一部戏
All your high-wire stunts have been an act.
一次又一次
Time after time,
你化险为夷  侥幸逃脱
you skip to the edge of the abyss, then dance away again.
可你却从未克服过你的恐惧
But you've never really conquered your fear.
自从那一天开始...
You've been afraid.
你就一直忧心忡忡
Ever since that day.
哪一天?
What day?
这一切都发生过
All of this has happened before
这一切会再次重演
and will happen again.
没锁
SOCRATA: It's open.
你好  妈妈
Hello, Mama.
没想到这只是六年前
It's hard to believe it's only six years ago.
你看起来年轻好多
You look so much younger.
是的
I was.
你真的做到了
SOCRATA: So, you really did it.
家里第一个当上军官的人
First person in the family to become an officer.
轮也该轮到我了
What is the world coming to?
卡拉 他们告诉我你是他们所见过最好的天生驾驶员的料
Kara, they tell me that you're the best natural pilot they've ever seen.
我第一次坐进驾驶舱的时候 我就...
First time I got in that cockpit, I just
觉得我属于那里
felt like I belonged.
那些都是天生的
All that natural ability,
不过你还是以班上第16名的成绩毕业的
and still, you only graduated sixteenth in your class.
117侯选人中第16名  妈妈
Sixteenth out of 117 cadets, Mama.
这有什么可骄傲的?
Why are you proud of that?
你应该是第一名
You should have been number one.
他们告诉我你的缺点够从这里排到爱诺朗了
They tell me that you have left a trail of demerits from here to Aerilon.
你无法无纪
You're undisciplined, you have no respect for authority...
这不关你的事了  妈妈
It's none of your business, anymore.
你有天分  卡拉
You have a gift, Kara.
我一直心里有数
I've always known that,
我不会让你就此荒废掉
here, in my gut and I am not going to let you piss that away.
你与众不同 难道你不明白吗?
You're special. Don't you understand that?
不  我不明白
No, I'm not!
你就不能放弃你那愚蠢的梦想吗?
Would you let go of that stupid dream of yours?
你没能当上军官  我很遗憾
Look, I am sorry as hell that you never made officer
这间破房子和墙上那些勋章
and all you have to show for a life of dedication
是你为国尽忠的唯一证明
is this crappy apartment and that frakking medal on the wall.
但我不会去弥补你的遗憾
But I will not make up for it all.
我做不到
I can't.
说得对  因为你就是个轻言放弃的人
Yeah, because you're a quitter.
一向如此
You always have been.
你去过肿瘤专家那里了?
You went to an oncologist?
放下  别碰
Hey! Put that down! Don't touch that!
你要怎么办?
What are you going to do about this?
不去管它
Nothing.
没什么办法  已经转移了
There's nothing to do. It's metastasized.
游戏结束了
Game is over.
我很遗憾  妈妈
I'm sorry, Mama.
别可怜我
I don't want your pity.
你还没得到我的怜悯
You haven't got it.
你想替别人难过?
You want to feel sorry for someone?
去为你自己难过吧
Feel sorry for yourself.
你得找别的方法  来督促自己了
You're gonna have to find another way to motivate your ass.
我陪不了你多久了
I'm not gonna be around to do it any longer.
可别告诉我还要哭啊
Oh, don't tell me you're gonna cry about it now.
我用不着在这里听这些话
You know what? I don't need this. I'm gonna...
我要走出那道门
I'm gonna walk out that door
你就自己走完  这段悲惨的日子吧
and you can look at it every frakking miserable day you have left
我永远也不会再迈过这道门槛
and know that I am never gonna come back through it again.
卡拉
Kara!
然后你就一直跑  对吧?
You kept running, didn't you?
跑了好几条街
For blocks.
她就一直在这里守着
LEOBEN: She waited here
等了五周 希望你能回来
for five weeks, hoping you'd come back.
她在孤独中死去
She died alone.
我害怕我会看不下去
I was afraid I couldn't watch.
还为时不晚
It's not too late.
她还在等你
She's waiting still.
妈妈
Mama.
你回来了
You came back.
想不到你还留着这些东西
I can't believe you kept all this.
所有的一切都留着
Everything.
一直如此
Always.
妈妈
Mama.
有事要发生了
Something's about to happen.
您还记得您一直让我有所准备的那件事吗?
You know that thing that you were trying to prepare me for?
我不知道自己是否能做到
I don't know if I can do it.
你能行的  能行的
Oh, yes, you can. You can.
为什么你这么肯定?
How can you be sure?
因为你是我的女儿
You're my daughter.
死亡并没有那么可怕
LEOBEN: See? There's nothing so terrible about death.
当你最终面对它的时候 它是如此美丽
When you finally face it, it's beautiful.
你自由了
You're free now.
可以找回真正的自己了
To become who you really are.
你不是李奥本
You're not Leoben.
从没说过我是
Never said I was.
我来这里 是为了让你准备好通过那道门
I'm here to prepare you to pass through the next door.
参透生死
To discover what hovers in the space between life and death.
星芭 我是阿波罗 我无法在雷达上看到你
Starbuck, Apollo. I lost you on dradis.
重复一遍...
I say again,
我看不到你
I've lost you.
启用应答机识别  我会确定你的方位
Squawk ident. I'll try to get a fix on you.
卡拉!
Kara!
李
STARBUCK: Lee.
我不怕了
I'm not afraid anymore.
再说一遍?
Say again?
我不怕了
I'm not afraid anymore.
她应该害怕
She should be afraid.
她已经很接近最低海拔高度了
She's damn close to the hard deck.
阿波罗离她也不远  压力会把他俩都挤个粉碎
Apollo's not far behind. The pressure will crush them both.
快  李 把她弄出来
Come on, Lee. Get her out of there.
90秒后到达最低海拔高度
GAETA: Ninety seconds to hard deck.
卡拉  听我说
All right, Kara. Listen to me.
别去管那该死的"烤面包机"了
Forget the damn toaster.
迅速爬升  不然你就死定了
Climb now or you're dead.
我们还能逃出来  还没有到达无法挽回的地步
We can still pull out of this. We haven't gone past the point of no return.
卡拉
Kara!
60秒后到达最低海拔高度
GAETA: Sixty seconds to hard deck.
小杜 按阿波罗上次的位置
Dee, vector red section to Apollo's last known.
从一号管道派出待战机
Set alert Vipers to ready one.
热狗  汉克斯  转为715号
DUALLA: Hotdog, Hex, divert to 715.
天杀的  你在哪里?
Gods, Starbuck, where are you?
看到了 看到了 好
Visual. Visual. Okay.
卡拉  我来接你了
Kara, I'm coming to get you.
李...
STARBUCK: Lee.
让我们在另一边见吧
I'll see you on the other side.
卡拉  求你听我说… 回来
APOLLO: Kara, please. Listen to me. Come back.
就让我去吧
Just let me go.
天杀的  卡拉!
Gods damn it, Kara.
你给我回来!  回来!
You come back! Come back!
没关系
It's okay.
就让我去吧
Just let me go.
他们在等我
They're waiting for me.
不!
No!
不!!
阿波罗!
Apollo!
离开那里!  取消任务!
Get out of there! Abort!
取消任务
Abort!
李 你看到她了吗? 能看到她吗?
Lee, do you have her in sight? Can you see her?
不能
APOLLO: Negative.
她…
She...
她进去了
She went in.
我们会立即派出搜救队
We're sending in the search and rescue birds right now.
会找到她的
We'll find her.
不用  爸 没用了
APOLLO: No, Dad. It's no use.
她的战机已经变成了碎片
Her ship's in pieces.
她的战机
Her ship
...没了
is lost.